Castle. After a few moments she came back to say that Dorothy and the
others were to be admitted at once The end of Chapter 22 this is a librivox
recording all librivox recordings are in the public domain for more information
or to volunteer please visit librivox.org this recording by jay Hall
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz by l frank Baum chapter 23 Glinda The Good Witch
Grants Dorothy’s Wish Before they went to see Glinda, however, they were taken to
a room of the Castle, where Dorothy washed her face and combed her hair, and
the Lion shook the dust out of his mane, and the Scarecrow patted himself into
his best shape, and the Woodman polished his tenant oiled his joints. When they
were all quite presentable they followed the soldier girl into a big room where
the Witch Glinda sat upon a throne of rubies. She was both beautiful and young
to their eyes. Her hair was a rich red in color and fell in flowing ringlets over
her shoulders. Her dress was pure white but her eyes were blue, and they looked
kindly upon the little girl. “What can I do for you, my child?” she asked. Dorothy
told the Witch all her story: how the cyclone had brought her to the Land of
Oz, how she had found her companions, and of the wonderful adventures they had met
with. “My greatest wish now,” she added, “is to get back to Kansas, for Aunt Em will
surely think something dreadful has happened to me, and that will make her
put on mourning; and unless the crops are better this year than they were last, I
am sure Uncle Henry cannot afford it.” Glinda leaned forward and kissed the
sweet, upturned face of the loving little girl. “Bless your dear heart,” she said, “I am
sure I can tell you of a way to get back
to Kansas she added, “But, if I do, you must give me the Golden Cap.” “Willingly!”
exclaimed Dorothy; “indeed, it is of no use to me now, and when you have it you can
command the Winged Monkeys three times.” “And I think I shall need their services
just those three times,” answered Glenda smiling. Dorothy then gave her the Golden
Cap, and the Witch said to the Scarecrow, “What will you do when Dorothy has left
us?” “I will return to the Emerald City,” he replied, “for Oz has made me its ruler and
the people like me. The only thing that worries me is how to cross the hill of
the hammerheads By means of the Golden Cap I shall command the Winged Monkeys
to carry you to the gates of the Emerald City,” said Glinda, “for it would be a shame
to deprive the people of so wonderful a ruler.” “Am I really wonderful?” asked the
Scarecrow. “You are unusual,” replied Glinda.
Turning to the Tin Woodman, she asked, “What will become of you when Dorothy
leaves this country?” He leaned on his axe and thought a moment. Then he said, “The
Winkies were very kind to me, and wanted me to rule over them after the Wicked
Witch died. I am fond of the Winkies, and if I could get back again to the Country
of the West, I should like nothing better than to rule over them forever.”
“My second command to the Winged Monkeys,” said Glinda “will be that they carry you
safely to the land of the Winkies. Your brain may not be so large to look at as
those of the Scarecrow, but you really are brighter than he is— —when you are
well polished— —and I am sure you will rule the Winkies wisely and well.” Then
the Witch looked at the big, shaggy Lion and asked, “When Dorothy has returned to
her own home, what will become of you?” “Over the hill of the hammerheads he
answered, “lies a grand old forest, and all the beasts that lived there have made me
their King. If I could only get back to this forest, I would pass my life very
happily there.” “My third command to the Winged Monkeys,” said Glinda, “shall be to
carry you to the forest. Then, having used up the powers of the Golden Cap, I shall
give it to the King of the Monkeys, that he and his band may thereafter be free
forevermore The Scarecrow and the Tin Woodman and the Lion now thanked the
Good Witch earnestly for her kindness; and Dorothy exclaimed: “You are certainly
as good as you are beautiful! But you have not yet told me
to get back to Kansas.” “Your Silver Shoes will carry you over the desert,” replied
Glinda. “If you had known their power you could have gone back to your Aunt Em the
very first day you came to this country.” “But then I should not have had my
wonderful brains!” cried the Scarecrow. “I might have passed my whole life in the
farmer’s cornfield.” “And I should not have had my lovely heart,” said the Tin Woodman.
“I might have stood and rusted in the forest till the end of the world.” “And I
should have lived a coward forever,” declared the Lion, “and no beasts in all
the forest would have had a good word to say to me.” “This is all true,” said Dorothy,
“and I am glad I was abused to these good friends. But now that each of them has
had what he most desired, and each is happy and having a kingdom to rule
besides, I think I should like to go back to Kansas.” “The Silver Shoes,” said the Good
Witch, “have wonderful powers. And one of the most curious things about them is
that they can carry you to any place in the world in three steps, and each step
will be made in the wink of an eye. All you have to do is knock the heels
together three times and command the shoes to carry you wherever you wish to
go.” “If that is so,” said the child joyfully, “I will ask them to carry me back to
Kansas at once.” She threw her arms around the Lions neck and kissed him, patting
his big head tenderly. Then she kissed the Tin Woodman, who was weeping in a way
most dangerous to his joints. But she hugged the soft, stuffed body of the
Scarecrow in her arms instead of kissing his painted face, and found she was
crying herself at this sorrowful parting from her loving comrades. Glinda the Good
stepped down from her ruby throne to give the little girl a goodbye kiss,
and Dorothy thanked her for all the kindness she had shown to her friends in
herself. Dorothy now took Toto up solemnly in her arms, and having said one
last goodbye she clapped the heels of her shoes together three times, saying:
“Take me home to Aunt Em!” Instantly she was whirled through the air, so swiftly
that all she could see or feel was the wind whistling past her ears. The Silver
Shoes took but three steps, and then she so suddenly that she rolled over upon
the grass several times before she knew where she was. At length, however, she sat
up and looked about her. “Good gracious!” she cried. For she was sitting on the
broad Kansas prairie, and just before her was the new farmhouse Uncle Henry built
after the cyclone had carried away the old one.
Uncle Henry was milking the cows in the barnyard, and Toto had jumped out of her
arms and was running towards the barn, barking furiously. Dorothy stood up and
found she was in her stocking feet For